Michael S. Irby

(864) 923-8262 • Washington, D.C. • msism720@gmail.com • msi-ism.github.io • linkedin.com/in/msi-ism/

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

A software engineer who is comfortable & confident in both front-end & back-end development with a specific knowledge of the MERN stack. After being a financial professional for 10 years, I desired a career change & since have completed hundreds of hours of software engineering study through personal projects & the Per Scholas software engineering bootcamp. Actively seeking employment with an innovative company where I can make an immediate impact & further my development as an engineer.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Technologies: HTML • CSS • Javascript • Typescript • Python • MongoDB • Express • React • Node

EDUCATION

Per Scholas - Washington, D. C Software Engineering Bootcamp November 2022 **University of South Carolina** - Columbia, SC Bachelor of Science in Sport & Entertainment Management May 2012 - Overall GPA: 3.2/4.0

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Grandbridge Real Estate Capital - Charlotte, NC

Treasury Operations Analyst

- Coordinated the disbursement of commercial loan proceeds from acquiring capital from our bank partner to preparing & initiating the wire for the funds to be sent to the title agent
- Prepared a daily reconciliation of the company's 3rd party escrow account against bank transaction history
- Prepared a monthly fee reconciliation of the company's pipeline against the company's General Ledger

Managed the day to day operations of the 3rd party escrow account which ranged from tracking & recording expense deposits to facilitating the payment of 3rd party expenses via ACH, check, & wire

- Calculated commissions earned for fee producers on a monthly basis
- Accurately processed over \$500 million worth of wires,
 ACHs, and checks during tenure with the company

LPL Financial Services - Charlotte, NC

New Client Onboarding Consultant

- Successfully transitioned registered financial advisors from their previous broker dealer to LPL Financial by completing a variety of onboarding duties
- Confidently & clearly communicated with advisors of all experience levels what was needed for onboarding via phone & email

August 2017-April 2018

August 2018-May 2022

- Processed and analyzed credit reports, background checks, and other reports as needed to pre-screen potential advisors
- Created custom production reports for management via Excel and Salesforce on a daily basis

AvidXchange, Inc - Charlotte, NC

Treasury Analyst

- Managed the daily operations and cash flow of the Invoice Accelerator factoring program as it related to Treasury
- Managed and consistently resolved an inventory of Treasury related cases via Salesforce CRM software

January 2016-Sept. 2016

- Responsible for initiating and reconciling thousands of dollars worth of ACH credits, debits, and wires on a daily basis
- Created custom (.csv) files to import customer account data into the AvidPay system

Paycom Software, Inc - Oklahoma City, OK

New Client Setup Specialist

- Managed projects involving the setup of payroll for several new clients concurrently
- Processed payroll for multiple clients on a weekly basis while observing applicable tax regulations

- December 2014 November 2015
- Contributed > \$150,000 of revenue for the company through payroll setups
- Consistently met crucial deadlines in a fast-paced and time sensitive environment